

# **Hassan Nahhal**

TORONTO, ON

nahhal.hasan@gmail.com

+1 (226) 600-3458

Energetic, target-oriented, collaborative, analytical problem-solver Software Developer with 3 years of experience in designing, implementing and testing solutions that help users with their digital transformation.

	<ul> <li>Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder</li> <li>Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I</li> <li>Salesforce Certified Administrator</li> <li>1st Place award for Best NexJ Systems Hackathon Project</li> <li>1st Place award for Best Mobile Solutions Capstone Project</li> </ul>		Oct 2020			
			Sep 2020			
			Jun 2020 Dec 2019 Aug 2016			
	<ul> <li>Graduated with High Distinction for</li> </ul>	rm Conestoga College	Aug 2016			
SKILLS						
	• Java	Object Oriented	 Design			
	<ul> <li>JavaScript</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Design Patterns</li> <li>Testing and Test Automation</li> <li>Debugging</li> <li>Source Control (Git and Mercuria)</li> </ul>				
	HTML and CSS					
	• SQL					
	• Scheme					
	<ul> <li>Salesforce Administration and</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Scrum and Scrum</li> </ul>	n tools (Jira and			
	Development	Azure DevOps)				
EMPLOYMENT						
Aug 2020 – Present	FULL STACK SALESFORCE DEVELOPER  EcoVadis  Increased user productivity by automating business processes using Lightning Process Builder.  Extended Sales Cloud functionality by creating custom fields.  Improved data quality by implementing Apex Triggers and unit tests with 100% code coverage.					
				Identified gaps and areas for improvement then provided action items		
				following <b>best practices</b> .		
				<ul> <li>Administered the organization by importing and cleansing records,</li> </ul>		
				identifying and giving user permissions, creating new users and other		
				<ul> <li>administrative tasks.</li> <li>Lead <b>agile transformation</b> by introducing and administering sprints, sprint</li> </ul>		
		planning, retrospectives and stan	d-ups.			
	Nov 2017 – Apr 2020	APPLICATION DEVELOPER				
		NexJ Systems	NexJ Systems			
		Implemented features and fixed bugs for Nex I's Customer Process				

- Implemented features and fixed bugs for NexJ's Customer Process Management System (CPM) based on **Stakeholders**' requirements.
- Integrated CPM with both NexJ's Enterprise Customer Relationship Management (CRM) and CRM for Wealth Management.
- Wrote unit tests to maintain quality and eliminate regressions.

- Helped Professional Services implement clients' requirements using CPM to improve and enforce compliance.
- Developed Progress Calculation with an intuitive UI to improve User
   Experience and increase Financial Advisors' productivity.
- Performed code reviews and took initiative to develop coding standards to maintain code base quality and increase readability.
- Administered Scrum processes including grooming, stand-ups, sprint planning and retrospectives.
- Documented features and bugs internally for each release to increase knowledge transfer.
- Integrated CPM with Salesforce's Sales Cloud by building REST APIs that
  push data to Heroku's PostgreSQL database, then retrieve them in
  Salesforce through Salesforce Connect. (Hackathon)

### Mar 2017 – Aug 2017

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Whut Inc (Contract)

- Investigated and fixed bugs for Whut's Content Management System (CMS) on both Web and iOS app.
- Integrated Whut's CMS with Salesforce's Sales Cloud using OpenID Connect, Visualforce pages and Apex.
- Built a PDF viewer using Mozilla's PDFJS in Angular2 and Ionic2.

Jan 2016 - Apr 2016

#### APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Blackberry (Co-op)

- Analyzed and optimized Oracle PL/SQL queries to improve performance.
- Wrote scripts for Windows and Linux that execute Oracle jobs.

#### EDUCATION

## May 2015 - Aug 2016

# MOBILE SOLUTIONS DEVELOPMENT (OCGC WITH CO-OP)

Conestoga College, Kitchener, Canada

- **GPA**: 3.93/4
- Capstone project: Receipt Keeper is a Web app built using Angular.js, and an Android app that uses Tesseract OCR engine to extract then persist and sync data, using LoopBack REST APIs, between local SQLite database and remote mLab database deployed to Heroku.

# Sep 2010 - Jun 2014

## **BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Beirut Arab University, Beirut, Lebanon

- **ABET** accredited
- **Senior project:** PocketShop is a **C2C** app built for Android devices and developed using **Java**, **PHP**, and **MySQL**. One of the major features is product **auto rating** based on users' review.

## SOCIAL







